SAAB CORTEX-1 AI DEFENSE SYSTEM
Full-stack C2 demonstration
Boreal Passage & Sweden AOR theaters
ACT 1 — CORTEX COMMAND PORTAL
Multi-theater C2 hub
Hovering: CORTEX C2 · KINETIC 3D · TACTICAL DISPLAY · SWARM · LIVE
ACT 2 — CORTEX C2 STRATEGIC CONSOLE
Strategic audit interface — live backend HTTP 200
Theater: BOREAL PASSAGE
Engine model: ELITE V3.5 selected
Scenario loading: SWARM ATTACK
Threat inventory populating...
Swarm scenario active — 12 MARV + cruise vectors
Doctrine cycling: FORTRESS → AGGRESSIVE → BALANCED
Blend ratio: 70%
[ENGINE] /run_audit → ELITE V3.5 · BALANCED doctrine
Dispatching Monte Carlo (200 runs)...
[RESULT] Strategic consequence score: +200.18
Tactical assignments: 30
All forward bases covered — THEATER NOMINAL
C2 panel scroll — COT feed and assignment grid visible
Panning across effector inventory and doctrine weights
Boreal Strategic Dashboard
ELITE model selected — doctrine cycle Fortress → Balanced
Map view loading MARV animation...
MARV-1 / MARV-2 / MARV-3 quadratic Bezier arcs from north
14% perpendicular control-point
Sinusoidal terminal jink grows in last 40% of approach
PAC-3 MSE intercept arcs confirmed — steep upward Bezier
Intercept fraction 0.72 — explosion flash 35px ring
2.2s pause between cascade events
ENGAGE deep-links:
MARV-1 → CALLHAVEN · MARV-2 → SOLANO · MARV-3 → MERIDIA
Swarm defense deep-link active
Dashboard Live MC audit dispatched
[ENGINE] scoring in real time...
Theater toggle: BOREAL → SWEDEN AOR preview → back to BOREAL
Map reloads confirm sensor overlay integrity across both theaters
ACT 3 — SWEDEN AOR STRATEGIC COMMAND
Stockholm-centered coordinate frame
11 Swedish military installations online
Sweden AOR map pan — Baltic ingress vectors confirmed
MARV-alpha / MARV-beta / MARV-gamma approaching from east
ACT 4 — KINETIC CHASE — PRO-NAV PHYSICS ENGINE
MARV-1 → CALLHAVEN · base=10 · dir=north · autorun=1
dt=0.1s · threat speed 3000 m/s (Mach 8.8) · max_g=42G
[PRO-NAV] Sinusoidal jink · magnitude 750 m/s · period 3.8s
Guidance constant N=4.0 — curved pursuit arc visible
MARV weaving left-right under terminal manoeuvre
Canvas 1.35x zoom — S-curve curvature confirmed
HUD: INTERCEPTED · miss distance · approach geometry nominal
ACT 5 — SWARM PHYSICS — MASS SATURATION ATTACK
3 simultaneous MARVs auto-launched after 1.2s
MARV-1 → CALLHAVEN · MARV-2 → SOLANO · MARV-3 → MERIDIA
[PAC-3 MSE] Oblique head-on intercept geometry
Fuse: 3000m — post-move proximity check active
Web Worker 20Hz physics: jinkMag 80-150 m/s per warhead
Cyan PAC-3 arcs vs orange MARV paths — all 3 interceptors locked
Canvas 1.4x zoom — intercept geometry fully visible
ACT 6 — BOREAL KINETIC 3D SIMULATOR
Three.js r128 intercept engine
Weapon: MARV · Outcome: INTERCEPT · Theater: BOREAL
[SIM] MARV-1 fired — sinusoidal terminal jink active
jinkDecay = 1-ct*1.3 — jink persists to 77% of flight
SAM Pro-Nav curves to chase laterally displaced target
MARV-1 intercept confirmed — detonation flash
MARV-2 second shot dispatched
[SIM] Saturation wave triggered — btn-wave
Multiple simultaneous MARV launches — mass attack profile
All intercepts resolved — theater nominal
ACT 7 — BOREAL TACTICAL DISPLAY
Radar canvas 1000x780px · SCALE 0.6 (1667 km theater)
Model: ELITE V3.5
PHASE A — AUTONOMOUS ENGAGEMENT
4 bomber threats spawned at eastern staging zone
SA mode: AUTO ENGAGE · Health bar: CRITICAL
[ENGINE] /evaluate_advanced — ELITE V3.5 · FORTRESS
Kill schedule fires: kills counter 0 → 4
SA health bar → SECTOR SECURE
PHASE B — HUMAN-IN-THE-LOOP OVERRIDE
Commander checks MANUAL OVERRIDE
SA mode badge: AUTO ENGAGE → MANUAL OVERRIDE
CHRONOSTASIS ACTIVE
Strategic Override Triggered — Simulation Frozen
Commander reviewing AI intercept recommendation
[COMMANDER] COMMENCE ENGAGEMENT authorized
fireWeapons() called with manual override
3x explosions cascade on radar canvas
PHASE C — SATURATION AMBUSH
Doctrine: AGGRESSIVE · btn-blind: 8 ghost threats
SA health: CRITICAL — ENGAGE
[ENGINE] AGGRESSIVE doctrine — 8x cascade explosions
Kill counter +8 · SA health bar → SECTOR SECURE
ACT 8 — SWEDEN AOR TACTICAL
Stockholm-centered frame · 11 installations · AGGRESSIVE doctrine
ELITE V3.5 · 4 Baltic threats spawned
[ENGINE] /evaluate_advanced — ELITE V3.5 · AGGRESSIVE
Score: -77.12 vs Boreal -380
Higher defense efficiency under denser installation coverage
ACT 9 — LIVE VIEW
Real-time telemetry log stream
Boreal theater event feed: kills · assignments · doctrine events
Portal return — all systems nominal across both theaters
DEMO COMPLETE
SAAB CORTEX-1 AI DEFENSE SYSTEM
Full-stack end-to-end capability demonstrated